我们怎么能让这个更小呢 ?
How can we make this even smaller?
我能想到的第一件事是
Well, the first thing I might think is
我只需要做些什么
what things do I only need for
just the build?
我有点暗示了，我不需要什么时候去生产， npm，对吧 ?
And I kind of hinted there, and I don't
need when I go to production, npm, right?
我在生产时就不需要包经理了
I actually don't need the package
manager when I'm in production.
我要在建筑的时候才需要它对吧
I just need it when I'm building it,
right?
同样地， npm 是那么小，它是数十兆字节 ( 如果是的话 ) 。
Again, npm is so small,
it's tens of megabytes, if that.
不需要这样做，我只是想向你说明一点。
Don't really need to do this, I just
wanted to demonstrate a point to you.
有时候如果你像鲁斯特或者 LLVM 之类的东西或者类似的东西
Sometimes if you're building things
like Rust or LLVM or things like that,
这些东西都是相当大的工具链
these things are quite large tool chains.
你不想派人去生产
And you don't wanna send
those out to production,
cuz 会再次出现安全漏洞。
cuz there are security
vulnerabilities again.
我要向你们展示如何做到这一点，但请不要这样做。
So I'm gonna show you the concept of how
to do this, but please don't do this for
npm ，这根本不是个好主意。
npm, it's just not in
general not a good a idea.
我猜是有情况的
Well, I guess there are scenarios, and
我们会在稍后取消晚上的时候去做个好主意
we'll actually get into that later,
when eliminating npm could be a good idea.
但是对于像这样一个节点应用程序，这不是一个大问题。
But for a node application like this,
it's not a big deal.
所以让我们更进一步，好吧。
So let's go even further, all right.
Docker 允许您执行称为 " 多阶段构建 " 的方法，即
So Docker allows you to do what's called
multistage builds, which is like let's
请先构建某些内容，然后将输出复制到新容器中，然后从该容器中进行处理。
build something first, copy the output
into a new container and go from there.
因此，我实际上可以多次构建多个容器。
So I can actually basically build
multiple containers multiple times.
所以，让我们继续做吧。
So let's go ahead and do that.
所以从第一个来说，因为这个第一个容器就是为了
So from the first one, because this
first container is going to be just for
建筑东西，我就说，酷，给我点 : 12 点，对吧 ?
building stuff, I'm just gonna say,
cool, give me node : 12-stretch, right?
我们把这些都搬到这里因为这不重要
And we'll move this all stuff down
here because it doesn't matter.
你最好把厨房给我好吗
Hey, so you might as well give
me the kitchen sink, right?
因为我要建一堆东西然后把这个集装箱扔了
Because I'm gonna build a bunch of stuff
then I'm gonna throw this container away.
因此，我将创建一个名为 WORKDIR / build的目录。
So I'm gonna make a directory
called WORKDIR /build.
所有内容都可以作为路由完成，因为它不重要，因为最终用户将
Everything can be done as route because it
doesn't matter because the end user will
不是航线
not be route.
所以我要说 WORKDIR / build
So I'm gonna say WORKDIR /build.
好吧那我就说吧
Okay, and then I'm gonna say copy.
事实上这里的东西你可以在这里做
Actually, this stuff right here,
you can totally do this down here.
在这里，因为它可以由 root 用户拥有，这不是什么大不了的。
Here on the chown because it can be
owned by root, that's not a big deal.
好的， RUN npm ci ，然后我们就会说
Okay, RUN npm ci and then we're gonna say,
复制 ...，好吗 ?
copy.., all right?
这里或下面的所有东西，都是建筑的舞台。
And so this everything above here or
below here, this is the build stage.
>> 并复制 ..，
&gt;&gt; And copy ..,
将此目录中的任何内容复制到同一个容器目录中。
is copy whatever is in this directory
into the same container directory.
>> ，是的，是的，它只复制了所有东西。
&gt;&gt; Exactly, yep,
yeah it just copies everything.
好的，然后在这里，我们要有一个运行时阶段。
Okay, and then down here,
we're gonna have a runtime stage.
所以你要做的就是重新开始
So what you're gonna do is
gonna say FROM again, but
我们要从一个不同的容器开始
we're gonna start with
a different container.
从高山上来说 : 3 . 10 ，好吗 ?
So FROM alpine: 3.10, okay?
我们将运行 APK 添加节点。
Here we're going to run APK add nodejs.
但我们不能用晚上的时间来做我们不需要在建筑阶段
But we're not going to do it with npm cuz
we don't need that in the build stage,
我们要去做我们的 RUN addgroup ，我们要做我们的用户节点，
we're goona do our RUN addgroup,
we're going to do our usernode,
我们要做米克迪尔可以做 WORKDIR
we're gonna do mikdir, who can do WORKDIR.
然后我们就不用再这样了
And then here,
we don't need to do this again,
因为上面已经发生过了
because it's already happened above.
事实上，我们不需要这些副本中的任何一个。
In fact,
we don't need either one of these copies.
但我们现在要做的就是复制我们要说的是
But what we're gonna do now is we're gonna
say copy,and we're gonna say --from,
这都是从这里来的对吧
that's what this from is right here,
right?
我们要从 0 级开始
And we're gonna say from stage 0.
现在你也可以拿到这些名字了，我不记得我头上的语法了，
Now you can also get these names, I don't
remember the syntax off the top my head,
但你可以把它叫做建筑之类的
but you could call this as build or
something like that.
>> 作为构建。
&gt;&gt; As build.
>> 很好，大家都记得我上次有头的时候，那是一个真正的风险。
&gt;&gt; Good has everyone remember the last
time I had my head, that was a real risk.
所以在那种情况下，你会看到来自建筑的副本，对吧。
So in that case you would see copy
from build, right., You see for
字号也是因为数字可能有点脆
words numbers also were because
numbers that can be a bit brittle
在多个阶段，您可以有五个阶段，对。
of multiple stages cuz you can
have like five stages, right.
从建造开始我们会说 chown
So from build, we're gonna say --chown
=节点 : 节点。
=node:node.
然后我们会从你的建筑里说你的所有东西
And then we're gonna say FROM /build,
everything that you put in /build,
把它放在这里还可以是这个工作目录
put it in here which still can
be this working directory.
然后在这里 CMD 也一样
And then down here the CMD stays the same.
一切都很好
Everything's all good.
顺便说一下这些指示你知道我一直在给他们
By the way, these like instructions,
you know how I'm always putting them
在上面的箱子里，他们其实不用上大写的，你就知道了。
in upper case, they actually don't have
to be in upper case, just so you know.
但每个人都让他们都这么做
But literally everyone makes
them all upper case so
这个文件更容易读读
that the file is a lot easier to read.
所以你不需要，但总是这样做。
So you don't have to, but always do it.
我觉得 VS 代码会改变我的状态
I actually think that VS code
will change this for me.
不会的但这会说嘿这事真蠢别这么做
No it won't but it's gonna say hey
this is real dumb, don't do that.
指示信息应以大写字体写，您是白痴。
Instructions should be written in
upper case letters, you idiot.
好吧那就好了
Okay, it would still work though.
好吧让我们看看这是否有用
All right, so let's see if this works.
这是任何人的猜测
It's anyone's guess.
其实更酷的是我现在要给你看的
What's actually even cooler,
which I'm now gonna show you,
你可以在一排里建一堆集装箱
you can actually build a bunch
of containers in a row.
所以你可以说，这是我的设备容器，这是我的建筑容器。
So you can say like, here's my dev
container, here's my build container.
您可以将它们全部构建在 dockerfile 中，并将其全部导出
You can build them all in on dockerfile
and it'll export all of them for
你也挺酷的
you, which is kind of cool too.
现在，我有了我的最新版本。
So now I have this my-node-app latest.
让我们向前看，看看我没有满地胡扯。
Let us go ahead and give it a run
to see that I am not full of crap.
可能吧没人知道
Might be, no one ever knows.
仍然在工作，仍然看到我们的成功。
Still working right,
still seeing our success.
让我们继续吧
Let's go ahead and stop this.
我必须说 Docker 会检查我的 -node-app | jq。
I must say docker inspect
my-node-app | jq.
让我们来看一看。
And let's take a look.
我们已降至 39 兆字节。
We are down to 39 megabytes.
所以我们就更小了
So we got even smaller, so
我们给自己留了 20 兆字节的东西
we saved ourselves 20 megabytes with
npm being gone, something like that.
我是说在理论上我想你甚至可以删除包裹 JSON
I mean, in theory, I guess you
could even drop package JSON and
软件包锁定 JSON 并保存一些额外的千字节。
package lock JSON and
save some extra kilobytes.
太好了别这样
Good for you, don't do that.
但是当你喜欢的时候你会明白的
But kind of get the point where you
kind of get through that like, okay,
我在生产中不需要什么对吧
what don't I need in production, right?
这就是我想通过你的想法
That's the idea that I
wanna get through you.
有时，在一个目录中有多个 Docker 文件。
Sometimes you have multiple
docker files in one directory.
一般来说，这不是真的，但它会发生，对吗 ?
In general, that's not true but
it can happen, right?
所以，让我们说我还有一个，可能就像我的发展环境。
So let's say I had another one here
that was maybe like my dev environment.
我将它称为 dev.dockerfile。
I would call it like dev.dockerfile.
还有很多争论，应该是 dockerfile.dev 还是
There's also a lot of debate,
should it be dockerfile.dev or
应该是 dev.dockerfile吗 ?
should it be dev.dockerfile?
我将以这种方式向您展示，因为语法突出显示了工作和
I'm going to show you this way because
that way syntax highlighting works and
我生命中的一切都是基于语法的突出显示
everything in my life is based
around syntax highlighting.
没有它我无法发展
I can't develop without it.
所以我们只能坚持这一点
So we're just sticking with that.
所以就这样说吧，我不知道来自 Node 的一些很傻的东西
So let's just say this, I don't know
something really dumb FROM Node
:latest 或类似的东西。
: latest or something like that.
问题就变成了如何在没有的情况下
The question then becomes
how do I build this without,
cuz 就会立即找到 Docker 文件的名称。
cuz this just immediately finds whatever
the name of the docker file is.
所以你也可以把 F
So you can also put in-F.
然后你就放进去了 dockerfile 那就是你说的
And then here you put in dev.dockerfile,
and that's how you pointed out a different
Docker 文件，或者它可能类似于目录的外部或类似的内容。
docker file, or it can be like outside
of the directory or something like that.